# **ZAKI AHMED**

zaki@zakiahmed.org | Houston, TX | (832) 483-2131 | www.zakiahmed.org

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software Developer with 2+ years of experience in an agile enterprise environment. I am proficient at creating web applications using front end/ back end technologies and creating custom designs and user experiences for both web and mobile applications. Comfortable managing multiple projects and maintaining quality client relationship.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, GoLang, HTML5, HAML

Web Application Tools: Rails, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, AngularJS (4), BackBoneJS, CSS3, SQL, Microsoft SQL Server Management

Studio 2012, AWS, Heroku, Git, Github

Other: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, MS Project, MS Office

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Avanade Inc. – Experience Technologist II; Houston, TX

Oct 2017 - Present

- Analyzed and revamped 2 legacy applications and created 3 new applications with modern designs and intuitive user experiences in the healthcare industry.
- Worked with user groups to iteratively create tailor made user experiences.
- Built modern, functional, and responsive web and mobile user interfaces.
- Developed and implemented efficient, reusable and flexible UI components using modern tools (e.g. JavaScript, CSS3, JQuery, HTML5)

### Waterfield Energy Software – Full Stack Developer; Tulsa, OK

Feb 2017 - July 2017

Developed, maintained, and upgraded accounting management software tailored specifically for the oil and gas industry in an agile environment utilizing Ruby on Rails, Go Language, CoffeeScript, SQL, BackBone.Js, HAML, CSS.

- Fulfilled custom feature requests from clients while working with Business Analysts to create new data manipulation options or UI features
- Created reusable application wide functions in regards to data manipulation or UI features
- Ported newly created functions and features application wide using global text replacement scripts.
- Fixed bugs throughout any module of the application in regards to both front and back end issues.
- Upgraded older sections of the application which utilized an outdated domain specific language to a purely Backbone.JS implementation

# **Sterling Engineering Group of Companies** – *Full Stack Developer;* Houston, TX

July 2016 - December 2016

- Created multiple web applications utilizing agile methodologies that aimed to solve problems in the construction industry (Design, UX, Front-End, and Back-End)
- Oversaw full project lifecycle from abstract concept to functional MVP brainstorming, architecture, development,
- Implemented regular testing and maintenance processes for all applications and trained team members on usage

# **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### **Tissue Sample Management Application** – *Avanade Inc.*

November 2017 - July 2018

- Redesigned a legacy healthcare application with concise workflows, new user experiences and built the resulting front end implementing modern design, UX and front end features.
- Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Adobe Photoshop

# **Concr.io** – Sterling Engineering Group of Companies

October 2016 – December 2016

- Developed a fully functional construction services platform which replaces the cumbersome bid process currently used in the concrete construction industry using calling and form requests. Concr.io allows general contractors to share uniform material takeoffs with subcontractors and manage the bidding process. Major features include user login system, user profiles, a price estimation equation, uploading and downloading to/from Amazon S3, an engineering support panel, and a bid management panel.
- Skills: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML, SCSS, AWS, Heroku

#### **EDUCATION**

The Iron Yard: Houston
The University of Houston

Back End Development Bootcamp
Bachelor of Science, Petroleum Engineering